type Question = {
  question: string;
  answers: string[];
  correctAnswer: string;
};

export const E2ovutoimplantationdata = {
  questions: [
    
        {
          question: "During which phase of the menstrual cycle does the uterine endometrium enter the proliferative phase?",
          answers: ["Follicular phase",
           "Ovulatory phase",
           "Luteal phase",
           "Menstrual phase",
           "Secretory phase"],
           correctAnswer: "Follicular phase"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which hormone is primarily responsible for the surge that triggers ovulation?",
           answers: ["Follicle-stimulating hormone (FSH)",
           "Luteinizing hormone (LH)",
           "Estrogen",
           "Progesterone",
           "Gonadotropin-releasing hormone (GnRH)"],
           correctAnswer: 2
        },
        {
          "question": "Which cells produce estrogen during the follicular phase?",
          answers: ["Theca interna cells",
           "Granulosa cells",
           "Lutein cells",
           "Syncytiotrophoblast cells",
           "Cumulus cells"],
           correctAnswer: "Granulosa cells"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which structure forms after the follicle ruptures and the oocyte is released?",
          answers: ["Corpus albicans",
           "Corpus luteum",
           "Graafian follicle",
           "Zona pellucida",
           "Cumulus oophorus"],
           correctAnswer: "Corpus luteum"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which of the following structures does the oocyte enter after ovulation?",
          answers: ["Uterus",
           "Cervix",
           "Fimbriae of the uterine tube",
           "Vagina",
           "Corpus luteum"],
           correctAnswer: "Fimbriae of the uterine tube"
        },
        {
          "question": "What hormone prevents the degeneration of the corpus luteum if fertilization occurs?",
          answers: ["Estrogen",
           "Progesterone",
           "Luteinizing hormone (LH)",
           "Human chorionic gonadotropin (hCG)",
           "Follicle-stimulating hormone (FSH)"],
          correctAnswer: "Human chorionic gonadotropin (hCG)"
        },
        {
          "question": "What is the main result of fertilization?",
          answers: ["Initiation of the acrosome reaction",
           "Completion of the first meiotic division",
           "Restoration of the diploid number of chromosomes",
           "Release of the second polar body",
           "Penetration of the zona pellucida"],
          correctAnswer: "Restoration of the diploid number of chromosomes"
        },
        {
          "question": "Where does fertilization typically occur in the female reproductive tract?",
          answers: ["Vagina",
           "Cervix",
           "Uterine cavity",
           "Ampulla of the uterine tube",
           "Isthmus of the uterine tube"],
          correctAnswer: "Ampulla of the uterine tube"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which process is essential for sperm to become capable of fertilizing an oocyte?",
          answers: ["Acrosome reaction",
           "Capacitation",
           "Zona reaction",
           "Cortical reaction",
           "Metaphase II arrest"],
          correctAnswer: "Capacitation"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which protein is involved in the acrosome reaction?",
          answers: ["Integrin",
           "Disintegrin",
           "ZP3",
           "Zona pellucida",
           "Zona reaction protein"],
          correctAnswer: "ZP3"
        }
      ] as Question[]
    };
//         ,
//         {
//           "question": "What is the first phase of fertilization?",
//           "option1": "Penetration of the corona radiata",
//           "option2": "Penetration of the zona pellucida",
//           "option3": "Fusion of the oocyte and sperm cell membranes",
//           "option4": "Capacitation",
//           "option5": "Acrosome reaction",
//           "ans": 1
//         },
//         {
//           "question": "What is the function of the zona pellucida during fertilization?",
//           "option1": "To produce estrogen",
//           "option2": "To facilitate sperm binding and induce the acrosome reaction",
//           "option3": "To secrete progesterone",
//           "option4": "To stimulate ovulation",
//           "option5": "To prevent polyspermy",
//           "ans": 2
//         },
//         {
//           "question": "What happens to the oocyte immediately after the spermatozoon enters it?",
//           "option1": "It undergoes the acrosome reaction",
//           "option2": "It completes meiosis I",
//           "option3": "It releases cortical granules to prevent polyspermy",
//           "option4": "It initiates capacitation",
//           "option5": "It degenerates",
//           "ans": 3
//         },
//         {
//           "question": "What forms as a result of the cortical and zona reactions?",
//           "option1": "Corona radiata",
//           "option2": "Zona pellucida",
//           "option3": "Cumulus oophorus",
//           "option4": "Male pronucleus",
//           "option5": "Corpus luteum",
//           "ans": 4
//         },
//         {
//           "question": "During which phase of fertilization does the sperm bind to the oocyte membrane?",
//           "option1": "Penetration of the corona radiata",
//           "option2": "Penetration of the zona pellucida",
//           "option3": "Fusion of the oocyte and sperm cell membranes",
//           "option4": "Capacitation",
//           "option5": "Acrosome reaction",
//           "ans": 3
//         },
//         {
//           "question": "Which hormone is secreted by the developing embryo to maintain the corpus luteum?",
//           "option1": "Estrogen",
//           "option2": "Progesterone",
//           "option3": "Luteinizing hormone (LH)",
//           "option4": "Human chorionic gonadotropin (hCG)",
//           "option5": "Follicle-stimulating hormone (FSH)",
//           "ans": 4
//         },
//         {
//           "question": "What structure is formed from the corpus luteum if pregnancy occurs?",
//           "option1": "Corpus albicans",
//           "option2": "Corpus luteum of pregnancy",
//           "option3": "Graafian follicle",
//           "option4": "Zona pellucida",
//           "option5": "Cumulus oophorus",
//           "ans": 2
//         },
//         {
//           "question": "What process occurs approximately 24 hours after fertilization?",
//           "option1": "Implantation",
//           "option2": "Blastocyst formation",
//           "option3": "Cleavage",
//           "option4": "Gastrulation",
//           "option5": "Neurulation",
//           "ans": 3
//         },
//         {
//           "question": "Which structure secretes progesterone to maintain pregnancy until the placenta takes over?",
//           "option1": "Corpus albicans",
//           "option2": "Graafian follicle",
//           "option3": "Corpus luteum",
//           "option4": "Syncytiotrophoblast",
//           "option5": "Hypothalamus",
//           "ans": 3
//         },
//         {
//           "question": "What is the fate of the inner cell mass of the blastocyst?",
//           "option1": "It forms the trophoblast",
//           "option2": "It forms the placenta",
//           "option3": "It forms the embryo",
//           "option4": "It forms the chorion",
//           "option5": "It forms the amnion",
//           "ans": 3
//         },
//         {
//           "question": "Which cells are involved in the formation of the placenta?",
//           "option1": "Granulosa cells",
//           "option2": "Trophoblast cells",
//           "option3": "Theca interna cells",
//           "option4": "Lutein cells",
//           "option5": "Syncytiotrophoblast cells",
//           "ans": 2
//         },
//         {
//           "question": "What is the primary function of the syncytiotrophoblast?",
//           "option1": "To form the inner cell mass",
//           "option2": "To produce human chorionic gonadotropin (hCG)",
//           "option3": "To secrete estrogen",
//           "option4": "To maintain the corpus albicans",
//           "option5": "To produce follicle-stimulating hormone (FSH)",
//           "ans": 2
//         },
//         {
//           "question": "At what stage is the developing embryo when it implants into the uterine wall?",
//           "option1": "Morula",
//           "option2": "Blastocyst",
//           "option3": "Gastrula",
//           "option4": "Neurula",
//           "option5": "Zygote",
//           "ans": 2
//         },
//         {
//           "question": "Which of the following statements about the morula is correct?",
//           "option1": "It has a blastocoel cavity",
//           "option2": "It contains more than 16 cells",
//           "option3": "It implants into the endometrium",
//           "option4": "It forms after the blastocyst stage",
//           "option5": "It is surrounded by the zona pellucida",
//           "ans": 2
//         },
        
//             {
//               "question": "Once the zygote has reached the two-cell stage, it undergoes a series of mitotic divisions. What are the resulting cells called?",
//               "option1": "Blastocysts",
//               "option2": "Morula",
//               "option3": "Blastomeres",
//               "option4": "Trophoblasts",
//               "option5": "Embryoblasts",
//               "ans": 3
//             },
//             {
//               "question": "During cleavage, at what stage do blastomeres maximize their contact with each other to form a compact ball of cells?",
//               "option1": "Two-cell stage",
//               "option2": "Four-cell stage",
//               "option3": "Eight-cell stage",
//               "option4": "Sixteen-cell stage",
//               "option5": "Morula stage",
//               "ans": 3
//             },
//             {
//               "question": "What structure forms about three days after fertilization, consisting of 16 cells?",
//               "option1": "Blastocyst",
//               "option2": "Morula",
//               "option3": "Zygote",
//               "option4": "Embryoblast",
//               "option5": "Trophoblast",
//               "ans": 2
//             },
//             {
//               "question": "What does the inner cell mass of the morula give rise to?",
//               "option1": "Placenta",
//               "option2": "Trophoblast",
//               "option3": "Embryo proper",
//               "option4": "Blastocyst cavity",
//               "option5": "Zona pellucida",
//               "ans": 3
//             },
//             {
//               "question": "During blastocyst formation, what is the cavity called that forms within the inner cell mass?",
//               "option1": "Blastocoel",
//               "option2": "Morula",
//               "option3": "Trophoblast",
//               "option4": "Embryoblast",
//               "option5": "Zona pellucida",
//               "ans": 1
//             },
//             {
//               "question": "What is the primary function of the trophoblast cells during the early stages of implantation?",
//               "option1": "To form the embryo proper",
//               "option2": "To form the inner cell mass",
//               "option3": "To penetrate the uterine mucosa",
//               "option4": "To secrete progesterone",
//               "option5": "To form the blastocoel",
//               "ans": 3
//             },
//             {
//               "question": "Which proteins are involved in the initial attachment of the blastocyst to the uterine epithelium?",
//               "option1": "Integrins",
//               "option2": "Selectins",
//               "option3": "Laminin",
//               "option4": "Fibronectin",
//               "option5": "Collagen",
//               "ans": 2
//             },
//             {
//               "question": "At what stage does the human blastocyst typically begin implantation into the uterine mucosa?",
//               "option1": "First day",
//               "option2": "Third day",
//               "option3": "Sixth day",
//               "option4": "Ninth day",
//               "option5": "Twelfth day",
//               "ans": 3
//             },
//             {
//               "question": "What is the outermost layer of the uterus called?",
//               "option1": "Endometrium",
//               "option2": "Myometrium",
//               "option3": "Perimetrium",
//               "option4": "Basal layer",
//               "option5": "Spongy layer",
//               "ans": 3
//             },
//             {
//               "question": "During the menstrual cycle, what phase follows ovulation and is influenced by progesterone?",
//               "option1": "Follicular phase",
//               "option2": "Proliferative phase",
//               "option3": "Menstrual phase",
//               "option4": "Secretory phase",
//               "option5": "Luteal phase",
//               "ans": 4
//             },
//             {
//               "question": "Which phase of the menstrual cycle involves the rebuilding of glands and arteries?",
//               "option1": "Menstrual phase",
//               "option2": "Proliferative phase",
//               "option3": "Secretory phase",
//               "option4": "Luteal phase",
//               "option5": "Ovulatory phase",
//               "ans": 2
//             },
//             {
//               "question": "What are the three distinct layers of the endometrium during the secretory phase?",
//               "option1": "Compact, spongy, and basal",
//               "option2": "Functional, basal, and muscular",
//               "option3": "Proliferative, secretory, and menstrual",
//               "option4": "Glandular, vascular, and muscular",
//               "option5": "Inner, middle, and outer",
//               "ans": 1
//             },
//             {
//               "question": "Where does the human blastocyst normally implant in the uterus?",
//               "option1": "Along the anterior wall",
//               "option2": "Along the posterior wall",
//               "option3": "In the cervical canal",
//               "option4": "In the fallopian tube",
//               "option5": "Along the anterior or posterior wall of the body of the uterus",
//               "ans": 5
//             },
//             {
//               "question": "What occurs if the oocyte is not fertilized?",
//               "option1": "The corpus luteum continues to grow",
//               "option2": "The endometrium assists in implantation",
//               "option3": "The endometrium is shed",
//               "option4": "The placenta takes over hormone production",
//               "option5": "The zona pellucida remains intact",
//               "ans": 3
//             },
//             {
//               "question": "What structure does the inner cell mass of the blastocyst form?",
//               "option1": "Trophoblast",
//               "option2": "Placenta",
//               "option3": "Embryo proper",
//               "option4": "Blastocoel",
//               "option5": "Zona pellucida",
//               "ans": 3
//             },
//             {
//               "question": "What hormone is primarily responsible for maintaining the corpus luteum if pregnancy occurs?",
//               "option1": "Estrogen",
//               "option2": "Progesterone",
//               "option3": "Luteinizing hormone (LH)",
//               "option4": "Human chorionic gonadotropin (hCG)",
//               "option5": "Follicle-stimulating hormone (FSH)",
//               "ans": 4
//             },
//             {
//               "question": "During which phase of the menstrual cycle does the uterine endometrium prepare for possible implantation of an embryo?",
//               "option1": "Menstrual phase",
//               "option2": "Proliferative phase",
//               "option3": "Secretory phase",
//               "option4": "Follicular phase",
//               "option5": "Ovulatory phase",
//               "ans": 3
//             },
//             {
//               "question": "What is the primary function of the corpus luteum during early pregnancy?",
//               "option1": "To produce estrogen",
//               "option2": "To produce progesterone",
//               "option3": "To stimulate ovulation",
//               "option4": "To form the placenta",
//               "option5": "To form the blastocoel",
//               "ans": 2
//             },
//             {
//               "question": "Which hormone is responsible for the development of the endometrial glands during the secretory phase?",
//               "option1": "Estrogen",
//               "option2": "Progesterone",
//               "option3": "Luteinizing hormone (LH)",
//               "option4": "Human chorionic gonadotropin (hCG)",
//               "option5": "Follicle-stimulating hormone (FSH)",
//               "ans": 2
//             },
//             {
//               "question": "Which phase of the menstrual cycle is associated with the shedding of the endometrial lining?",
//               "option1": "Follicular phase",
//               "option2": "Proliferative phase",
//               "option3": "Secretory phase",
//               "option4": "Menstrual phase",
//               "option5": "Luteal phase",
//               "ans": 4
//             },
//             {
//               "question": "At what stage of development does the human blastocyst begin implantation into the uterine mucosa?",
//               "option1": "First day",
//               "option2": "Third day",
//               "option3": "Sixth day",
//               "option4": "Ninth day",
//               "option5": "Twelfth day",
//               "ans": 3
//             },
//             {
//               "question": "What structure contributes to the formation of the placenta?",
//               "option1": "Inner cell mass",
//               "option2": "Outer cell mass",
//               "option3": "Blastocoel",
//               "option4": "Zona pellucida",
//               "option5": "Embryoblast",
//               "ans": 2
//             },
//             {
//               "question": "During blastocyst formation, what is the cavity called that forms within the inner cell mass?",
//               "option1": "Blastocoel",
//               "option2": "Morula",
//               "option3": "Trophoblast",
//               "option4": "Embryoblast",
//               "option5": "Zona pellucida",
//               "ans": 1
//             },
//             {
//               "question": "Which hormone is primarily responsible for the thickening of the endometrium during the proliferative phase?",
//               "option1": "Estrogen",
//               "option2": "Progesterone",
//               "option3": "Luteinizing hormone (LH)",
//               "option4": "Human chorionic gonadotropin (hCG)",
//               "option5": "Follicle-stimulating hormone (FSH)",
//               "ans": 1
//             },
//             {
//               "question": "What layer of the uterus undergoes significant changes during the menstrual cycle?",
//               "option1": "Endometrium",
//               "option2": "Myometrium",
//               "option3": "Perimetrium",
//               "option4": "Basal layer",
//               "option5": "Spongy layer",
//               "ans": 1
//             },
//             {
//               "question": "What is the primary function of the trophoblast cells during early pregnancy?",
//               "option1": "To form the embryo proper",
//               "option2": "To form the inner cell mass",
//               "option3": "To secrete estrogen",
//               "option4": "To penetrate the uterine mucosa",
//               "option5": "To form the blastocoel",
//               "ans": 4
//             },
//             {
//               "question": "What structure does the trophoblast form that is crucial for implantation?",
//               "option1": "Placenta",
//               "option2": "Inner cell mass",
//               "option3": "Embryo proper",
//               "option4": "Blastocoel",
//               "option5": "Zona pellucida",
//               "ans": 1
//             },
//             {
//               "question": "Which cells are primarily responsible for the production of human chorionic gonadotropin (hCG) during early pregnancy?",
//               "option1": "Trophoblast cells",
//               "option2": "Granulosa cells",
//               "option3": "Theca cells",
//               "option4": "Corpus luteum cells",
//               "option5": "Syncytiotrophoblast cells",
//               "ans": 5
//             },
//             {
//               "question": "At what stage is the developing embryo when it implants into the uterine wall?",
//               "option1": "Morula",
//               "option2": "Blastocyst",
//               "option3": "Gastrula",
//               "option4": "Neurula",
//               "option5": "Zygote",
//               "ans": 2
//             },
//             [
//                 {
//                   "question": "A 28-year-old woman presents with amenorrhea and a positive pregnancy test. Ultrasound reveals a gestational sac without an embryo, consistent with an anembryonic pregnancy. What is the most likely cause of this condition?",
//                   "option1": "Chromosomal abnormalities",
//                   "option2": "Maternal infection",
//                   "option3": "Maternal autoimmune disease",
//                   "option4": "Hormonal imbalances",
//                   "option5": "Environmental toxins",
//                   "ans": 1
//                 },
//                 {
//                   "question": "A 32-year-old woman undergoing fertility treatment develops severe ovarian hyperstimulation syndrome (OHSS). What is the primary cause of OHSS?",
//                   "option1": "Excessive estrogen production",
//                   "option2": "Multiple ovarian cysts",
//                   "option3": "Increased vascular permeability",
//                   "option4": "High levels of progesterone",
//                   "option5": "Ovarian torsion",
//                   "ans": 3
//                 },
//                 {
//                   "question": "A newborn presents with ambiguous genitalia. Genetic testing reveals 46,XX karyotype with congenital adrenal hyperplasia. What enzyme deficiency is most likely responsible for this condition?",
//                   "option1": "21-hydroxylase",
//                   "option2": "11β-hydroxylase",
//                   "option3": "17α-hydroxylase",
//                   "option4": "3β-hydroxysteroid dehydrogenase",
//                   "option5": "5α-reductase",
//                   "ans": 1
//                 },
//                 {
//                   "question": "A 30-year-old woman with a history of recurrent spontaneous abortions is found to have antiphospholipid syndrome. Which of the following is a common feature of this syndrome?",
//                   "option1": "Recurrent pregnancy loss",
//                   "option2": "Severe preeclampsia",
//                   "option3": "Fetal growth restriction",
//                   "option4": "Placental abruption",
//                   "option5": "Gestational diabetes",
//                   "ans": 1
//                 },
//                 {
//                   "question": "A 35-year-old pregnant woman is diagnosed with gestational diabetes. Which of the following is a potential complication for the fetus?",
//                   "option1": "Macrosomia",
//                   "option2": "Microcephaly",
//                   "option3": "Neural tube defects",
//                   "option4": "Congenital heart defects",
//                   "option5": "Cleft palate",
//                   "ans": 1
//                 },
//                 {
//                   "question": "A 25-year-old woman presents with primary amenorrhea and short stature. Physical examination reveals a webbed neck and widely spaced nipples. What is the most likely diagnosis?",
//                   "option1": "Turner syndrome",
//                   "option2": "Klinefelter syndrome",
//                   "option3": "Androgen insensitivity syndrome",
//                   "option4": "Mayer-Rokitansky-Küster-Hauser syndrome",
//                   "option5": "Polycystic ovary syndrome",
//                   "ans": 1
//                 },
//                 {
//                   "question": "A 32-year-old woman with infertility is found to have polycystic ovary syndrome (PCOS). Which of the following is a common feature of PCOS?",
//                   "option1": "Hyperandrogenism",
//                   "option2": "Hypoandrogenism",
//                   "option3": "Hyperprolactinemia",
//                   "option4": "Hypothyroidism",
//                   "option5": "Hyperinsulinemia",
//                   "ans": 1
//                 },
//                 {
//                   "question": "A 28-year-old woman presents with pelvic pain and irregular periods. Imaging reveals an ovarian cyst. Which type of ovarian cyst is most likely associated with endometriosis?",
//                   "option1": "Follicular cyst",
//                   "option2": "Corpus luteum cyst",
//                   "option3": "Dermoid cyst",
//                   "option4": "Endometrioma",
//                   "option5": "Theca lutein cyst",
//                   "ans": 4
//                 },
//                 {
//                   "question": "A 33-year-old woman in her second trimester presents with painless vaginal bleeding. Ultrasound reveals a low-lying placenta. What is the most likely diagnosis?",
//                   "option1": "Placenta previa",
//                   "option2": "Placental abruption",
//                   "option3": "Vasa previa",
//                   "option4": "Chorioamnionitis",
//                   "option5": "Gestational trophoblastic disease",
//                   "ans": 1
//                 },
//                 {
//                   "question": "A 29-year-old woman presents with severe pelvic pain and a positive pregnancy test. Ultrasound reveals an ectopic pregnancy. Where is the most common site for an ectopic pregnancy?",
//                   "option1": "Ovary",
//                   "option2": "Cervix",
//                   "option3": "Abdominal cavity",
//                   "option4": "Fallopian tube",
//                   "option5": "Myometrium",
//                   "ans": 4
//                 },
//                 {
//                   "question": "A 36-year-old woman presents with a history of heavy menstrual bleeding and pelvic pressure. Ultrasound reveals multiple uterine fibroids. What is the most likely origin of these fibroids?",
//                   "option1": "Endometrial stroma",
//                   "option2": "Myometrium",
//                   "option3": "Perimetrium",
//                   "option4": "Serosa",
//                   "option5": "Cervical epithelium",
//                   "ans": 2
//                 },
//                 {
//                   "question": "A 30-year-old woman presents with a history of infertility and cyclic pelvic pain. Laparoscopy reveals pelvic adhesions and chocolate cysts. What is the most likely diagnosis?",
//                   "option1": "Endometriosis",
//                   "option2": "Adenomyosis",
//                   "option3": "Pelvic inflammatory disease",
//                   "option4": "Ovarian torsion",
//                   "option5": "Asherman's syndrome",
//                   "ans": 1
//                 },
//                 {
//                   "question": "A 35-year-old woman presents with abnormal uterine bleeding and is diagnosed with endometrial hyperplasia. Which of the following is a major risk factor for endometrial hyperplasia?",
//                   "option1": "Prolonged estrogen exposure",
//                   "option2": "Progesterone deficiency",
//                   "option3": "Androgen excess",
//                   "option4": "Hypothyroidism",
//                   "option5": "Chronic anovulation",
//                   "ans": 1
//                 },
//                 {
//                   "question": "A 28-year-old woman presents with a positive pregnancy test and hyperemesis gravidarum. Ultrasound shows a 'snowstorm' pattern with no fetus. What is the most likely diagnosis?",
//                   "option1": "Complete hydatidiform mole",
//                   "option2": "Partial hydatidiform mole",
//                   "option3": "Missed abortion",
//                   "option4": "Ectopic pregnancy",
//                   "option5": "Choriocarcinoma",
//                   "ans": 1
//                 },
//                 {
//                   "question": "A 32-year-old woman at 34 weeks' gestation presents with sudden onset of painful vaginal bleeding. What is the most likely diagnosis?",
//                   "option1": "Placenta previa",
//                   "option2": "Placental abruption",
//                   "option3": "Vasa previa",
//                   "option4": "Uterine rupture",
//                   "option5": "Cervical insufficiency",
//                   "ans": 2
//                 }
//               ]
              
              
// ]